SIMRANJOT KAUR

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



+1437-973-1397



taneja.simranjot@gmail.com



3666 St Clair Avenue East, Scarborough, ON M1M 1T2

Summary

Enthusiastic and Motivated Software Engineering post-grad student at Humber College, looking for internship opportunity to learn and master the technical skills acquired in classroom. Having 4+ years of professional in developing Web-based enterprise applications using cutting-edge technologies whilst gaining working knowledge of SDLC, Agile methodologies, Service Oriented Architectures, Web services and more.

Skills

- Operating System: Linux, Windows, macOS
- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, C++
- Web technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular
- Version Control Tools: Git, IBM Rational Clearcase, SVN
- CD/Cl Tools: Jenkins
- Testing Tools/Technologies: JUnit (Mockito, PowerMockito), Jasmine, HP ALM
- Graphic Designing Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Corel DRAW

Experience

YesWeCode (2022 - Present)

Calgary, Canada

Coding Instructor Volunteer

- Managing tutoring sessions for under-served communities with multiple students simultaneously.
- Created course curriculum for kids to learn Java and contributed in creating engaging learning environment to enhance student confidence and interest to learn.

Sopra Steria (2018 - 2022)

Delhi, India

Senior Software Engineer

- Developed and Deployed high-quality application that managed information about semi-conductors using Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, and Wildfly14 on Linux Server.
- Involved in developing SOAP and REST based web services for providing and consuming.
- Exposure to IDEs like Eclipse, Visual Studio Code and code management tools like SVN, ClearCase, GIT.
- Experienced working in Agile Scrum methodology.
- Expert in Testing Frameworks like JUnit, Power Mockito, Jasmine.

Ramanan Corporation (2015 - 2017)

Delhi, India

Application Engineer Intern

- Contributed in designing and developing web application which bridged gap between designers and developers.
- Led team of 4 members, and involved in building applications based on DOM manipulation and event-driven system.
- Designed custom google polymer components fulfilling project specific needs.

Education

2022- Present

Humber College, Canada

Post Graduation Diploma

2014-2018

Guru Gobind Singh Inderprastha University

Bachelors of Technology

Enrolled in Information Technology Solutions program at Humber College, IGS campus

Completed Bachelors of Technology in Computer Science with first division in distinction scoring 83.3%.

References

Amit Kumar

Team Lead, Sopra Steria

amitkumar2@soprasteria.com